<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<article>
	<preamble> 
		Alexandrov_2015_A Modified Tripartite Model for Document Representation in Internet Sociology.pdf 
	</preamble>
	<titre> 
		A Modiﬁed Tripartite Model for Document
	</titre>
	<auteur> Representation in Internet SociologyMikhail Alexandrov1,2, Vera Danilova1,2(B), and Xavier Blanco11 Autonomous University of Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain{MAlexandrov.UAB,XblancoE}@gmail.com2 Russian Presidential Academy of National Economy and Public Administration,Moscow, Russian Federationvera.danilova@e-campus.uab.cat </auteur>
	<abstract> tripartite model of actors, concepts and instances for document repre-sentation in the study of social networks. We propose a modiﬁed model,where instead of document authors we consider textual mentions of per-sons and institutions as actors. This representation proves to be moreappropriate for the solution of a range of Internet Sociology tasks. In thepaper we describe experiments with the modiﬁed model and provide somebackground on the tools that can be used to build it. The model is testedon the experimental corpora of Russian news (educational domain). Theresearch reﬂects the pilot study ﬁndings. </abstract>
	<biblio>
		1. Alexandrov, M.: Development of general methodology for analysis of public opinion
		of Internet-community and its application to given topics (authority, economy,
		corruption, etc.) on the basis of Data/Text Mining tools. Report on State project
		84, RPANEPA [rus] (2013)
		2. Alexandrov, M., Beresneva, D., Makarov, A.: Dynamic vocabularies as a tool for
		studying social processes. In: Proceedings of the 6th International Conference on
		Intelligent Information and Engineering Systems, ITHEA Publishing, vol. 27, pp.
		88–92 (2014)
		3. Alexandrov, M., Danilova, V., Koshulko, A., Tejada, J.: Models for opinion classi-
		ﬁcation of blogs taken from Peruvian Facebook. In: Proceedings of the 4th Interna-
		tional Conference on Inductive Modeling (ICIM-2013), Kyiv, Ukraine Publishing
		House ITRC-NASU (Ukraine) & Czech Technical University pp. 241–246 (2013)
		4. Alexandrov, M., Gelbukh, A., Rosso, P.: An approach to clustering abstracts.
		In: Montoyo, A., Mu˜noz, R., M´etais, E. (eds.) NLDB 2005. LNCS, vol. 3513,
		pp. 275–285. Springer, Heidelberg (2005)
		5. Alexandrov, M., Gelbukh, A., Makagonov, P.: Evaluation of thematic structure
		of multidisciplinary documents and document ﬂows. In: Proceedings of the 11th
		International DEXA Workshop (Database and Expert System Applications), pp.
		125–129 (2000)
		6. Baeza-Yates, R., Ribero-Neto, B.: Modern Information Retrieval. Addison Wesley,
		Boston (1999)
		7. Bishop, C.: Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning. Springer, Berkeley (2006)
		8. Danilova, V., Alexandrov, M., Blanco, X.: A survey of multilingual event extraction
		from text. In: M´etais, E., Roche, M., Teisseire, M. (eds.) NLDB 2014. LNCS,
		vol. 8455, pp. 85–88. Springer, Heidelberg (2014)
		9. Danilova V., Popova S.: Socio-political event extraction using a rule-based app-
		roach. In: Meersman, R., Panetto, H., Mishra, A., Valencia-Garcia, R., Soares, A.L.,
		Ciuciu, I., Ferri, F., Weichhart, G., Moser, T., Bezzi, M., Chan, H. (eds.) Proceedings
		of the 13th International Conference on Ontologies, DataBases and Applications of
		Semantics (ODBASE’2014), vol 8842, pp. 537–546, Springer (2014)
		10. Gelbukh, A., Sidorov, G., Guzman-Arenas, A.: Use of a weighted topic hierarchy for
		document classiﬁcation. In: Matouˇsek, V., et al. (eds.) TSD 1999. LNCS (LNAI),
		vol. 1692, pp. 133–138. Springer, Heidelberg (1999)
		11. Manning, C., Raghavan, P., Schutze, H.: Introduction to Information Retrieval.
		Cambridge University Press, Cambridge (2008)
		12. Eissen, S.M., Stein, B.: Analysis of clustering algorithms for web-based search.
		In: Karagiannis, D., Reimer, U. (eds.) PAKM 2002. LNCS (LNAI), vol. 2569, pp.
		168–178. Springer, Heidelberg (2002)
		13. Mika, P.: Ontologies are us: a uniﬁed model of social networks and semantics. J.
		Web Semant. Sci. Serv. Agents World Wide Web 5(1), 5–15 (2007)
		14. Stein, B., Niggemann, O.: On the nature of structure and its identiﬁcation. In:
		Widmayer, P., Neyer, G., Eidenbenz, S. (eds.) WG 1999. LNCS, vol. 1665, p. 122.
		Springer, Heidelberg (1999)
		
	</biblio>

</article>
